

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Spanish (native) English



CONTACT

- ☆ Medellin, Colombia
- **1** +57 3108597333
- ✓ sdelosrios95@gmail.com
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/santia godelosrios/?locale=en_US
- % http://santiagodelosrios.co/

SANTIAGO DE LOS RIOS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER ENGINEER

Software Developer Engineer offering six years of experience in frontend and backend development, delivering high quality products that solve client's needs. Also have experience as team leader, estimating user stories using agile methodologies, negotiating with the client and mentoring team members.. Lately I have been a Tech Screener, performing interviews and evaluations for candidates.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Gorilla Logic, Colombia | 12/2020 - Present

Backend and Fullstack (Node/React) developer for US clients. Performed as a Tech Lead in one of the projects and served as a Tech Screener for the company.

Senior Software Engineer

Globant, Medellin | 08/2020 - 12/2020

Backend developer in a project for the Disney Account and I I've been trained to be a Technical Leader. In this process I successfully led the production deployment for the application.

Web UI Developer

Globant, Medellin | 05/2018 - 07/2020

Led the Frontend team in a project for an important health institution in Colombia, estimating user stories using agile methodologies, mentoring junior members and developing new features.

Freelancer/Software Developer

Clientmaker, Cali | 11/2017 - 05/2018

Successfully designed and developed an API using NodeJS, Typescript, Gulp and MongoDB.

Fullstack Developer

Clientmaker, Cali | 06/2017 - 05/2018

Led the development of a web app for an important financial institution in Cali, Colombia.

Freelancer/Software Developer

Calido.co, Raleigh, EEUU | 12/2016 - 05/2017

Successfully designed and developed an API using NodeJS and Cassandra DB

EDUCATION

2012 - 2017

Telematics Engineering - Cum Laude degree

Universidad Icesi, Cali

Academic Awards:

- - Laureate Thesis Award
- - Honor roll Student: Inside the top ten out of +120 students in Telematics Engineering.